# Patrick Liddy - Creative Technologist

pjliddy@gmail.com

% www.pliddy.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/patrickliddy

github.com/pjliddy

**\$57.222.8177** 

I am a full stack developer with a passion for user experience. I am a designer who understands the technologies that bring designs to life. With over 25 years experience leading projects with emerging technologies, I love to design and build in both the digital and physical worlds. Being fluent in the languages of design, technology, and business, I practice a lean, interdisciplinary approach to solving any problems.

# Skills

# **Design & Strategy**

- UX Design and Research
- Digital Strategy
- Design Thinking
- · Lean & Agile Methodolgies
- Team Leadership

## Front End Technologies

- HTML5/CSS3
- Javascript/jQuery
- · Bootstrap/Handlebars
- Ember.js
- Git/GitHub

# **Full Stack Technologies**

- Node.js/Express
- · SQL & MongoDB
- · Ruby on Rails
- Python
- · Amazon Web Services

# **Experience**

Web Developer 2017-Present

Realizing the need for team members with strong skills in both design and technology, I completed a 12-week, 600+ hour web development bootcamp. Learning a variety of languages and frameworks, I leveled up my skills with the latest development technologies. I am to be able to rapidly prototype MVPs as part of a lean product development process or build full-stack applications as part of a team.

# Web Development Intensive General Assembly Mar 17-Jun 17
# CS50x: Intro to Computer Science HarvardX Feb 17-Mar 17

UX Designer 2007–2017

For the previous ten years, I focused on user experience design, working for small- to mid-sized digital agencies in Boston. I am fluent in all aspects of UX research and design for responsive web and mobile. I led teams on projects ranging from \$400K to \$2M for clients including Reebok, adidas, TripAdvisor, Hospira, and Travellers. I was responsible for planning, estimating, and budgeting, and delivery. Working closely with my development teams, I architected technical solutions, including a hybrid iOS app with off-line functionality and on-demand content updates and a custom CMS interfaces for use by non-technical audiences. During this time I also pursued graduate study in population-based conflict.

| # Director, UX                 | Medullan            | Nov 15-Jan 17 |
|--------------------------------|---------------------|---------------|
| # VP, Digital Strategy         | Partners+Simons     | Nov 13-Apr 15 |
| # Sr. UX Designer              | Communispace        | Jan 13-Nov 13 |
| # Assoc. Creative Director, UX | Freelance @ Sapient | Mar 12-Jan 13 |
| # Assoc. Director of Strategy  | Isobar              | Jul 11-Dec 11 |
| # Sr. UX Designer              | Isobar              | Jul 10-Jul 11 |
| # UX Designer                  | Isobar/Molecular    | Apr 07-Jul 10 |



## **Fabrication Designer**

2001-2006

Based in Las Vegas, I applied my digital skills to the design of home automation systems, interactive water features, and theatrical scenery. The breadth of projects allowed me to explore diverse applications of technology, including programmable logic controllers, CAD and 3D animation and rendering, RAID 5 servers for home media distribution, and the establishment of a large-format printing operation with CNC capabilities. I also learned fabrication techniques using wood, metal, plastics, and basic electronics.

# Digital Media Specialist

S & M Scenic

Jun 03-Jun 06

# Design Consultant

Freelance

Mar 01-Jun 03

Interactive Developer

1995-2001

As an developer, I designed and coded a variety of applications across multiple platforms and delivery media, including optical, kiosk, and online. I specialized in interactive museum exhibits, including the Best Software for Kids Gallery at the Computer Museum, which won a Best of Boston award from Boston Magazine. The system I created to allow network delivery of applications led to the founding of Softricity, where I was one of the first employees, and which was eventually acquired by Microsoft. As an early subject matter expert in interactive design, I also taught several graduate courses in the Computer Science department at Harvard Extension School.

| # Director of Software Certification | Softricity         | Jan 00-Mar 01 |
|--------------------------------------|--------------------|---------------|
| # Human Factors Engineer             | Softricity         | Aug 99-Jan 00 |
| # Sr. Interactive Developer          | Chedd/Angier       | Jun 97-Aug 99 |
| # Instructor                         | Harvard University | Jan 95-Jun 98 |
| # Interactive Developer              | Freelance          | Jan 95-Jun 97 |

Visual Designer 1990-1995

As a visual designer, I developed my skills in design, branding, marketing, digital media production, and publishing automation. I also continued my formal education in design and computer science.

# Staff Assistant Harvard University Oct 92-Jan 95 # Graphic Designer Freelance Oct 90-Oct 92



# Education

#### Graduate Courses in Government

Harvard University Sep 06-May 10

## Graduate Courses in Computer Science & Design

Jan 93-May 94 Harvard University

### Bachelor of Arts in Economics

University of Pennsylvania Sep 86-Jun 90

# Interests

- Metalworking
- Woodworking
- IoT & Home Automation
- History & Strategy
- Cooking
- Knitting